<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business-Standard on Clint McGuire</title>
    <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/tags/business-standard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business-Standard on Clint McGuire</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 21:10:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.clintmcguire.com/tags/business-standard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Five Tips to Secure M365 Business Standard</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/five-tips-to-secure-m365-business-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 21:10:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/five-tips-to-secure-m365-business-standard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-improve-security-in-m365&#34;&gt;How to improve security in M365&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has added a lot of security features to the M365 platform, but not all of them are available to all license levels.&#xA;If you are licensed for M365 Business Standard you won&amp;rsquo;t have access to all the security features in the platform, so let&amp;rsquo;s focus on what&#xA;is available to your tenant and review the Top 5.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup multi-factor authentication for all users&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create dedicated admin accounts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Filter out commonly malicious attachments from email&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use mail flow rules to warn users about potentially dangerous attachments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use mail flow rules to prevent auto-forwarding of email&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-these-improve-security&#34;&gt;How do these improve security?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-multi-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;1. Multi-factor Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enabling multi-factor authentication (MFA) for all users adds an additional layer of security when your users login. Since all M365 is hosted in the cloud,&#xA;the only way to verify access is by username and password - unless you also have MFA enabled. Before organizations moved to M365, they would often have a&#xA;server in their office, with a firewall protecting the office network from the outside. Limiting who was able to talk to the server. Since M365 is on the&#xA;internet, everyone has access. If an attacker can guess your users&amp;rsquo; usernames and passwords then they can get in.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Enabling MFA greatly complicates things for an attacker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
