<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft 365 Security on Clint McGuire</title>
    <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/categories/microsoft-365-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft 365 Security on Clint McGuire</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.clintmcguire.com/categories/microsoft-365-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SPF, DKIM, DMARC: The Email Authentication Trinity</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/spf-dkim-dmarc-the-email-authentication-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/spf-dkim-dmarc-the-email-authentication-trinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spf-dkim-dmarc-the-email-authentication-trinity&#34;&gt;SPF, DKIM, DMARC: The Email Authentication Trinity&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-summary&#34;&gt;Research Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Email authentication protocols (SPF, DKIM, and DMARC) represent the foundational security layer that municipal IT teams must implement before advanced M365 security features can reach maximum effectiveness. Current research reveals a critical vulnerability: 93.3% of government domains that suffered email spoofing attacks had not enabled email authentication even in monitoring mode, despite these protocols being free to implement and requiring only DNS configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Email Security Crisis Hiding in Plain Sight</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/the-email-security-crisis-hiding-in-plain-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/the-email-security-crisis-hiding-in-plain-sight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-email-security-crisis-hiding-in-plain-sight&#34;&gt;The Email Security Crisis Hiding in Plain Sight&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;content-strategy&#34;&gt;Content Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-premise-validation&#34;&gt;Content Premise Validation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Argument Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;: YES - The &amp;ldquo;hidden crisis&amp;rdquo; premise is exceptionally strong for municipal C-suite. The research reveals a perfect storm: organizations believe they&amp;rsquo;re protected (purchased M365 Business Premium), but they&amp;rsquo;re operating with minimal protection due to default configurations. This creates a false sense of security that C-suite leaders will immediately recognize as a governance and fiduciary risk. The argument is logical, evidence-based, and speaks directly to C-suite concerns about risk oversight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shared Responsibility and FOIPPA: What Municipal IT Teams Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/shared-responsibility-and-foippa-what-municipal-it-teams-need-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/shared-responsibility-and-foippa-what-municipal-it-teams-need-to-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When municipalities move to Microsoft 365, they often assume that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s compliance certifications mean automatic FOIPPA compliance. This assumption can be costly. The shared responsibility model means that while Microsoft secures the infrastructure, municipalities remain responsible for their data governance, access controls, and compliance obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding where Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities end and yours begin is critical for maintaining FOIPPA compliance in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-shared-responsibility-model-explained&#34;&gt;The Shared Responsibility Model Explained&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the shared responsibility model:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The FOIPPA Compliance Gap Hiding in Your M365 Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/foippa-compliance-gap-hiding-in-m365/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 07:40:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/foippa-compliance-gap-hiding-in-m365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOI requires 1 year retention. M365 defaults: Deleted emails gone forever after 30 days. Your compliance gap: 335 days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The city&amp;rsquo;s legal counsel calls your office. The development company&amp;rsquo;s lawyer is demanding to know why key emails about the rezoning decision are missing from the FOI response. &amp;ldquo;This looks like deliberate destruction of evidence,&amp;rdquo; they&amp;rsquo;re saying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your FOI coordinator explains that staff deleted routine emails months ago, and your IT systems automatically purged them after 30 days. The lawyer isn&amp;rsquo;t buying it. &amp;ldquo;Government records disappearing during a controversial decision? We&amp;rsquo;ll see you in court.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASR Rules - Hidden Security Controls</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/asr-rules-hidden-security-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 22:47:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/asr-rules-hidden-security-controls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hidden-security-controls-that-could-have-prevented-canadas-biggest-ransomware-attacks&#34;&gt;The Hidden Security Controls That Could Have Prevented Canada&amp;rsquo;s Biggest Ransomware Attacks&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, Canadian organizations paid ransom demands 79% of the time when attacked—meaning cybercriminals are successfully monetizing their operations four out of five attempts. For context, that&amp;rsquo;s a higher success rate than most legitimate businesses achieve with their core products.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In February of that same year, the City of Hamilton faced every IT leader&amp;rsquo;s nightmare. Despite actively working to improve their cybersecurity posture—including an ongoing multi-factor authentication rollout—attackers found gaps in their defenses and exploited them before the security improvements could be completed. The outcome: $18.3 million in immediate response costs, denied insurance coverage, and budget impacts that will affect taxpayers through 2027.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Tips to Secure M365 Business Standard</title>
      <link>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/five-tips-to-secure-m365-business-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 21:10:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.clintmcguire.com/blog/five-tips-to-secure-m365-business-standard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-improve-security-in-m365&#34;&gt;How to improve security in M365&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has added a lot of security features to the M365 platform, but not all of them are available to all license levels.&#xA;If you are licensed for M365 Business Standard you won&amp;rsquo;t have access to all the security features in the platform, so let&amp;rsquo;s focus on what&#xA;is available to your tenant and review the Top 5.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup multi-factor authentication for all users&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create dedicated admin accounts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Filter out commonly malicious attachments from email&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use mail flow rules to warn users about potentially dangerous attachments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use mail flow rules to prevent auto-forwarding of email&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-these-improve-security&#34;&gt;How do these improve security?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-multi-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;1. Multi-factor Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enabling multi-factor authentication (MFA) for all users adds an additional layer of security when your users login. Since all M365 is hosted in the cloud,&#xA;the only way to verify access is by username and password - unless you also have MFA enabled. Before organizations moved to M365, they would often have a&#xA;server in their office, with a firewall protecting the office network from the outside. Limiting who was able to talk to the server. Since M365 is on the&#xA;internet, everyone has access. If an attacker can guess your users&amp;rsquo; usernames and passwords then they can get in.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Enabling MFA greatly complicates things for an attacker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
